Guide to the Caroline Bien Papers, 1960s-2006 and undated RL.10988
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
Caroline Bien papers
1960s-2006 and undated
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
Bien, Caroline
John W. Hartman Center for Sales, Advertising & Marketing History
RL.10988
5 Linear Feet
Copywriter and executive at several U.S. advertising agencies, including Warwick & Legler, D'Arcy MacManus & Masius/deGarmo and Grey Advertising. Collection spans 1960s-2006 and includes proofs and tearsheets, correspondence, printed material, storyboards and other materials documenting Bien's career in advertising. Companies and products represented include Campho-Phenique, D-Con, Gerber, Helena Rubenstein, Karo, Mazola, Midol, Panasonic, Pepsi, Playtex, Seagram, and Timex. Acquired as part of the John W. Hartman Center for Sales, Advertising & Marketing History.
Related Materials
Related materials may be found in the following Hartman Center collections:
Alvin Achenbaum Papers
Foote, Cone & Belding Communications, Inc. Records
J. Walter Thompson Company. Bertram Metter Papers
J. Walter Thompson Company. Burt Manning Papers
Warwick Baker O'Neill Records
Provenance
The Caroline Bien Papers were received by the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library as a gift in 2012 and 2014.
Biographical note
Biographical Timeline
1965-1966 Martin Landey, fashion copywriter
1966-1968 Warwick & Legler
1968-1971 D'Arcy MacManus & Masius
1974-1979 Thompson-Koch
1979-1981 D'Arcy MacManus & Masius/deGarmo, Copy Supervisor
1983-1984 PepsiCo Summerfare Arts Festival, Advertising Director
1984-2006 Grey Worldwide, Vice President and Associate Creative Director
Access Restrictions
Collection is open for research.
However, original audiovisual materials are closed until use copies can be produced.
Researchers must register and agree to copyright and privacy laws before using this collection.
All or portions of this collection may be housed off-site in Duke University's Library Service Center. The library may require up to 48-hours to retrieve these materials for research use.
Please contact Research Services staff before visiting the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library to use this collection.
Collection Overview
Collection spans 1960s-2006 and includes proofs and tearsheets, correspondence, printed material, storyboards and other materials documenting Bien's career in advertising. Companies and products represented include Campho-Phenique, D-Con, Gerber, Helena Rubenstein, Karo, Mazola, Midol, Panasonic, Pepsi, Playtex, Seagram, and Timex. Acquired as part of the John W. Hartman Center for Sales, Advertising & Marketing History.
Advertising executives -- United States; Proofs (printed matter); Advertising agencies -- Executives; Advertising executives; Tear sheets; Storyboards; Advertising -- United States; Advertising -- United States -- History; Advertising; Gerber Products Company; Reckitt Benckiser (Firm); Grey Advertising, Inc.; PepsiCo, Inc.; Bien, Caroline; John W. Hartman Center for Sales, Advertising & Marketing History; Helena Rubenstein, Inc.; Distillers Corporation -- Seagrams Ltd
- Audiovisual Materials, 1987-2006 and undated; 1
  - RL10988-3/4-0001. Caroline Bien: Mazola Corn Oil: Exactly One. Campho-Phenique: Penetrating America. Muhammed Ali: More Power to You. Gerber Toddler Meals: Butler. Campho-Phenique: The Unexpected. Midol: A Woman's Right. 3/4 inch. Original, undated (Box 1)
  - RL10988-3/4-0002. Grey Advertising: Massengill: Mirror :15; Mirror Alt TRT :15; Mirror Alt :30. 3/4-inch. Original, 1995 Jan. 5 (Box 1)
  - RL10988-3/4-0003. Grey Worldwide: WebMD: Answers LLNT-2066 TRT :60. Answers Agency Version TRT :600. 3/4-inch. Original, 2002 Sept. 10 (Box 1)
  - RL10988-3/4-0004. Caroline Bien: Copywriter. 3/4-inch. Original, 1990 Sept. 5 (Box 1)
  - RL10988-3/4-0005. Grey Advertising: Massengill: Window Set CBS TRT :30, Window Seat ABC TRT :30, Massengill Billboard TRT :10. 3/4-inch. Original, 1987 May 29 (Box 1)
  - RL10988-3/4-0006. Grey: Panasonic Video Storyboard: Marfa. 3/4-inch. Original, Undated. (Box 1)
  - RL10988-3/4-0007. Grey Advertising: Panasonic: American Vignettes TRT :30. 3/4-inch. Original, 1990 Apr. 30 (Box 1)
  - RL10988-3/4-0008. Caroline Bien: Copywriter. 3/4-inch. Original, 1990 Sept. 5 (Box 1)
  - RL10988-3/4-0009. Grey Advertising: Massengill Feminine: Cleansing Wash: Three Women BEMA-1053 TRT :30. BEMA-1065 TRT :15. 3/4-inch. Original, 1991 Apr. 1 (Box 1)
  - RL10988-3/4-0010. Grey Worldwide: Proctor and Gamble/ Aventis Actonel: Warrior/Newsweek TRT :60, Warrior/Family Circle TRT :60, Warrior/Reader's Digest TRT :60. 3/4-inch. Original, 2001 Jan. 19 (Box 1)
  - RL10988-3/4-0011. Grey Advertising: Beecham Calgon Bubble Bath: Going Pink Bananas w/ Logo TRT :30, Pink Bananas Boy Logo TRT :15, Pink Bananas Girl Logo TRT :15, Hot Milk Logo TRT :15. 3/4-inch. Original, 1988 Feb. 9 (Box 1)
  - RL10988-3/4-0012. Grey Advertising: Novartis Consumer Health: Good Morning American Rev. 1 TRT :30. 3/4-inch. Original, 1998 Feb. 11 (Box 1)
  - RL10988-3/4-0013. Grey Worldwide: Proctor and Gamble/Aventis Actonel: Warrior/Woman's Day Rev. 2 TRT :60. 3/4-inch. Original, 2001 June 13 (Box 1)
  - RL10988-3/4-0014. Caroline Bien: Copywriter. 3/4-inch. Original, 1990 Sept. 5 (Box 1)
  - RL10988-3/4-0015. Grey Advertising: Novartis: Ex-Lax: Snooper Rev. TRT :30, Snooper Alt. Line Rev. TRT :30. 3/4-inch. Original, 1999 Aug. 31 (Box 1)
  - RL10988-3/4-0016. Grey Advertising: Proctor and Gamble: Downy: Clouds TRT :30, A Man and His Shirt TRT :30. 3/4-inch. Original, 1994 Aug. 15 (Box 1)
  - RL10988-3/4-0017. Grey Advertising: Massengill: Why Douche 3P TRT :30, Why Douche V/W TRT :15, :Why Douche :15. 3/4-inch. Original, 1991 May 24 (Box 1)
  - RL10988-3/4-0018. Grey Advertising: Jacuzzi and Pool. TRT :30. 3/4-inch. Original, 1996 Feb. 9 (Box 2)
  - RL10988-3/4-0019. Grey Advertising: Hanging Out. 3/4-inch. Original, 1995 July 5 (Box 2)
  - RL10988-3/4-0020. Grey Advertising: Why Massengill-Strangers (x2 BEMA-3015, one Alternate)(x2BEMA-3025, one Alternate) TRT :15 each. 3/4-inch. Original, 1993 Feb. 1 (Box 2)
  - RL10988-3/4-0021. Grey Worldwide: Detective TRT :45. Everywhere TRT :45. 3/4-inch. Original, Undated. (Box 2)
  - RL10988-3/4-0022. Denture Cream: First Spot. 3/4-inch. Original, Undated. (Box 2)
  - RL10988-3/4-0023. D-Con Four/Gone-Muhammed Ali. Campho-Phenique-Penetrating America. Mazola Corn Oil: Exactly One. Know Gelatine Drink-Lift a Finger. Gerber Toddler Meals: Japanese. Campho: Phenique: The Downs. GerberToddler Meals: Butler. Campho: Phenique: The Unexpected. Midol: A Womens Rights. Bigelow Carpets: Gemini. 3/4-inch. Original, Undated. (Box 2)
  - RL10988-3/4-0024. Gery Worldwide: Detective TRT :45. Everywhere TRT :45. 3/4-inch. Original, Undated. (Box 2)
  - RL10988-3/4-0025. Gery Worldwide-Film Noir Reel. Detective, Everywhere, Bridge. 3/4-inch. Original, 2006 Feb. 6 (Box 2)
  - RL10988-3/4-0026. Grey Advertising: Beach Rev #1 TRT :30 and Beach TRT :30. 3/4-inch. Original, 1988 Jan. 25 (Box 2)
  - RL10988-3/4-0027. P + G: cb:cw. 3/4-inch. Original, 2002 Jan. 28 (Box 2)
  - RL10988-VHS-0001. Playtex Users. VHS. Original, 1992 Mar. 11 (Box 2)
  - RL10988-VHS-0002. Grey Worldwide Proctor and Gamble/Aventis: Nurse Medizine Magazine TRT 60:00. VHS. Original, 2001 Oct. 4 (Box 2)
  - RL10988-VHS-0003. Gery Worldwide: Film Noir Reel. Detective, Everywhere, Bridge. VHS. Original, Undated. (Box 2)
  - RL10988-VHS-0004. Unlabeled. VHS. Original, Undated. (Box 2)
  - RL10988-VHS-0005. Unlabeled. VHS. Original, Jan. 18 (Box 2)
  - RL10988-VHS-0006. Caroline Bien Pnd. VHS. Original, Undated. (Box 2)
  - RL10988-VHS-0014. Grey Advertising: Calgon After-Bath Lotion: Bubble Silhouette TRT :15. VHS. Original, 1988 May 18 (Box 2)
  - RL10988-DVD-0001. Grey Worldwide: Flonase: Everywhere TRT :45. Everywhere TRT :30. Everywhere TRT :15. Everywhere TRT :10. DVD. Original, 2004 Oct. 5 (Box 2)
  - RL10988-16mm-0001. Caroline Bien. 16mm. Original, Undated. (Box 2)
  - RL10988-VHS-0007. Cialis: Creative Presentation. VHS. Original, 2001 Nov. 16 (Box 3)
  - RL10988-VHS-0008. Grey Advertising: Panasonic: American Vignettes. VHS. Original, 1990 Apr. 30 (Box 3)
  - RL10988-VHS-0009. Grey Worldwide: Flonase: Bridge TRT :30. Bridge/ Reminder TRT :15. Bridge/Refill TRT :15. VHS. Original, 2005 July 25 (Box 3)
  - RL10988-VHS-0010. Unlabeled. VHS. Original, Undated. (Box 3)
  - RL10988-VHS-0011. Grey Advertising: Why Massengill-Strangers (x2 BEMA-3015, one Alternate)(x2BEMA-3025, one Alternate) TRT :15 each. VHS. Original, 1993 Feb. 2 (Box 3)
  - RL10988-VHS-0012. Caroline Bien: Copywriter. VHS. Original, 1990 Sept. 5 (Box 3)
  - RL10988-VHS-0013. Grey Advertising: Massengill: Stream Room (x2) TRT :30. VHS. Original, 1996 Nov. 18 (Box 3)
- Professional Files, 1960s-2006 and undated; 2
  - Correspondence, 1979-2001 (Box 4)
  - Resumes, 2006 and undated (Box 4)
  - D'Arcy Macmanus & Masius/deGarmo--Mazola, 1980 (Box 4)
  - D'Arcy Macmanus & Masius/deGarmo--Olsten, 1980 (Box 4)
  - Fashion advertisements (Valor, Wilroy), 1960s (Box 4)
  - Free-lance work for William Esty--Dristan Ultra Cold Formula, 1982 (Box 4)
  - Grey Advertising--Massengill, 1990 and undated (Box 4)
  - Miscellaneous advertisements--Abreva, Calgon, Campho-Phenique, Karo, Midol, Seagram, Timex, 1976-2005 and undated (Box 4)
  - Pepsico Summerfare Arts Festival, 1984 (Box 4)
  - Thompson-Koch--D-Con, 1975-1978 (Box 4)
- Large Format Creative, 1960s-2004 and undated; 3
  - D'Arcy Macmanus & Masius/deGarmo--Olsten, Karo syrup, Mazola, 1979-1981 (Box 5)
  - Fashion--Delton (featuring Buster Keaton), Macy's, Valor, Weeds, 1960s (Box 5)
  - Grey Advertising--Flonase, Gerber Baby Food, Massengill, Panasonic, Rogaine, 1988-2004 (Box 5)
  - Electra Sol, Helena Rubenstein, Julius Kessler Whiskey, Seagrams, undated (Box 5)
  - Laminates--Actonel, Rogaine, 1997 and undated (Box 5)
  - Mounted storyboards--Campho-Phenique, D-Con, undated (Box 5)
  - Pepsico Summerfare Arts Festival, 1984 (Box 5)
  - Playtex tampons, undated (Box 5)
  - Thompson-Koch--D-Con, 1975-1978 (Box 5)
  - Thompson-Koch--Glenbrook Laboratories (Campho-Phenique, Kaopectate, Midol), 1976-1977 (Box 5)
  - Timex, 1967 and undated (Box 5)